Hello, I'm

Julia Pauletti

RICHARDSON, TX 75082 (469) 463-7528 julia.pauletti@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/juliapauletti/

Github: github.com/jpauletti

Portfolio: jpauletti.github.io/Portfolio

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with 3+ years of experience in UX design and development. Experience working with multiple clients on various projects at the same time. Passionate about blending design and functionality. Creative problem solver who is always eager to learn new things. Values communication and enjoys collaborative working environments.

Skills

HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars, React, Git, Node.js, Express, Firebase, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Litmus, Silverpop, Sketch, Invision, site maps, wireframes, user journeys/flows

Experience

JULY 2017 - PRESENT

Commerce House, Dallas, TX - UX Designer/Front-End Developer

Work with clients on a variety of digital projects while collaborating with account managers, strategists, designers, and developers to provide clients with a high-quality final product.

- UX:
 - Site maps, wireframes
 - User journeys, user flows
 - Information Architecture
- Front-End Development:
 - HTML email development including testing in Litmus and Silverpop
 - Develop banner ads using Google Web Designer and GreenSock
 - Work with development team on website requirements, development, launch, maintenance, and site updates
 - o Manage content, site set up, and conduct client training

FEB 2017 - JULY 2017

YourCause, Plano, TX - Product & Strategy Designer

- Innovated User Experience Design from web to application design. Coordinated closely with product managers, engineers, and account managers to ensure smooth delivery, maximized team collaboration, and the highest possible product quality. Developed low and high fidelity prototypes as well as final visual design deliverables.
- My responsibilities included: user and use-case research, UX architecture, and UI design. Worked within existing style guides and patterns, while continuing to push the envelope for better user experiences.

AUG 2016 - FEB 2017

Ryon's Web Design, Allen, TX - Web Marketing & Design

Worked with WordPress to create and maintain websites as well as their SEO. Managed multiple projects at once
including troubleshooting, communicating with clients, and keeping a consistent brand across the company's online
presence. Designed mock-ups of websites for new clients.

Education

FEB 2019 - AUG 2019

Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX - Full Stack Web Development

AUG 2013 - MAY 2016

UT Dallas, Richardson, TX - Emerging Media & Communication